Guide to the Hermine Duthie Decker Plays 1941-1977
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Hermine Duthie Decker Plays
1941-1977
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA, 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 124
Decker, Hermine Duthie
1 foot of linear shelf space 2 boxes
This collection is comprised of 22 typescripts of plays, one with original and revised editions, written by Hermine Duthie Decker.
Hermine Duthie Decker (1908-1996) graduated from Washington State College in 1930 with a speech degree. During her student years at WSC, Decker was the college sweetheart of future journalist Edward R. Murrow. Upon creation of the Old Slocum House Theatre Company in Vancouver, Washington, she became its first president. The company's first play, staged at the Slocum House in 1972, was written by Hermine Duthie Decker and titled, "Esther Short, A Heroic Pioneer Mother."
Hermine Duthie Decker was Head of the Speech and Drama department at Clark College, where she remained until her retirement.
This collection is comprised of 22 typescripts of plays, one with original and revised editions, written by Hermine Duthie Decker. Several of the manuscripts include notes or letters addressed to Professor Maynard Lee Daggy of Washington State College, asking for his criticism.
Additionally, the collection includes item lists, photographs of performances, an excerpt from a letter to Mrs. Mary Avery, and a WSU Hilltopics article about Hermine Duthie Decker and the Slocum House in Vancouver, Washington.
This collection is arranged in a single series.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection was donated to the Washington State University Libraries by Mrs. Maynard Daggy (1962) and Hermine Duthie Decker (1969).
Edward R. Murrow Papers, 1928-1932 (Cage 673).
Dramatists, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence
Performing Arts; Vancouver (Wash.)
- "Bury the Roots Deep" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Oscar takes over" - manuscript, 1948 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Such Ingratitude!" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "A Sheaf from the Hell-Box" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "The Chess Player" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "The Festered Lily" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "What? No Genii?" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "The Waves Roll in" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Bury the Roots Deep" - manuscript, 1941 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Be Yu Elopin'?" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Yesterday and Today" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "The Fly Watched" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Incognito" - manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "The Vanishing Hairline" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- "Too Big" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- "Radio Play" - manuscript, 1945 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- "The Great Diamond Robbery" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- "Esther Short - A Heroic Pioneer Mother" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- "Bury the Roots Deep" - manuscript (revision), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- "The Brown Primrose" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- "Please Fold, Staple---and Mutilate" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- "The Last Step" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- "A Very Delicate Subject" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "Once Around Jupiter" - manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous - excerpt from a letter to Mrs. Mary Avery from Hermine Duthie Decker and a WSU Hilltopics article, 1962, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)